FULL STACK ENGINEER WITH 10 YEARS OF PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE

My Personal Portfolio demonstrates the skill set I have acquired over the last ten years.



Software Engineer With Ten Years of Programming Experience

Phone: +1 (210) 585-6279 Email: dreebarrera@gmail.com

Austin, Texas, USA

www.drebarrera.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/drebarrera/

www.github.com/drebarrera

EDUCATION

BSE in Computer Engineering Purdue University | 2022

FEATURED CERTIFICATIONS

Udemy Next.js & React - The Complete Guide

MongoDB Python Development

AWS Technical Essentials Certification

Udemy Golang Course Certification

LANGUAGES

C & C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Dart, Golang, PHP, SQL, Java, Assembly, Verilog, MATLAB

FRAMEWORKS

React, Next.js, Node.js, Angular, Flutter, TailwindCSS, SassCSS, Bootstrap, Amazon Web Services (AWS), MySQL, MongoDB, WordPress, Prometheus, Grafana, Selenium, Chrome Extensions, RTI DDS, VBA, SQL, NoSQL, JSON & API Development, Docker, Wix, Figma, Photoshop, SVG, Semrush, YoastSEO, and many more!

See my Manifesto for more information.

WORK EXPERIENCE



December 2023 - June 2024

Software Engineer

Developing web applications and supporting backend infrastructure for a startup dedicated to creating a safer digital dating scene.

Skills: Angular, SassCSS, Bootstrap, Docker, Java Spring, Figma, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, WordPress, Flutter, Dart, YoastSEO, Semrush



May 2023 - Current

President | Software Engineer

Leading and developing content for a non-profit dedicated to elevating the Latino tech community. Read the <u>Case Study</u>.

Skills: Leadership, Next.js, React, TailwindCSS, Figma, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop

FATHOM5

June 2022 - July 2023

Software Engineer

Defense Software Modernization: Modernizing the US Navy's tactical weapons system. Read the <u>Case Study</u>.

EV Systems Architecture: Designing R&D circuits and firmware for the next generation of electric vehicles. Read the <u>Case Study</u>.

Skills: C++, Python, React, Node.js, Docker, Prometheus, Grafana, RTI DDS, GitHub, Linux, Draw.io, KiCAD, Beagle Board, Arduino, Linux, Texas Instruments, Nordic, Solidworks, Draw.io, Adafruit, GitHub



August 2021 - December 2022

Frontend Engineer

Building website and brand content for a startup which takes drone footage to new heights. Read the <u>Case Study</u>.

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Python, Wix, Adobe Photoshop, Final Cut Pro

FULL STACK ENGINEER WITH 10 YEARS OF PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE

My Personal Portfolio demonstrates the skill set I have acquired over the last ten years.



Full Stack Engineer with 10 Years Experience

I have devoted my educational and professional life to developing efficient code, designing beautiful content, and engineering next generation products.

In middle school and high school, I would dedicate my recess time to developing websites and creating programming tutorial videos for my classmates.

Since then, I have continued my path of engineering expertise with professional experience in software, firmware, and cloud orchestration. As an engineer I am passionate, ambitious, and own every one of my projects.



I graduated from Purdue University with a Bachelor's of Science in Computer Engineering.



I got my programming start through Codecademy's programming courses in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and <u>Python</u>.



My skill set ranges from frontend web development to system-on-chip firmware. I have over 10 years experience in major programming languages and a formal education in Computer Engineering.

Learn More

To learn more about me, check out my personal <u>Portfolio</u> and <u>Manifesto</u>.

